A Guide to the Papers of John Powell, 1888-1978, n.d.
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
- Series I.: Correspondence
  - Subseries B.: Other Correspondence
    - Correspondence, n.d., 28 items. (Box-folder 27:10)
      Correspondents include Pritzi Kerry to Betty Brockenbrough; Ruth Conray; Mrs. C. W. Read, Jr. to George Pullen Jackson; Mary Stevens to Betty Brockenbrough.
- Series II.: Manuscripts and Related Materials
  - A. Manuscripts: John Powell.
    Articles, catalog order lists for books and songs, course materials, performance and program notes, reviews, scores, songs and lyrics; speeches. These are arranged alphabetically by type of material.
    - John Powell to Dear Juniors for Music Magazine, October-November 1933, TM, 3 pp (Box-folder 28:1)
    - Folk Singers at the White House by John Powell and Annabel Buchanan, n.d., TM, 25 pp. (Box-folder 28:2)
    - Music and the Individual by John Powell, n.d., TM, 21pp. (Box-folder 28:3)
    - Music and The Nation by John Powell, n.d., TM, 50 pp. (Box-folder 28:4)
    - Virginia Finds Her Folk Music by John Powell, n.d., TM, 20 pp. There are also copies of earlier drafts. (Box-folder 28:5)
    - Catalog order lists for books, and songs, n.d., 27 items. (Box-folder 28:6)
      These are notes and advertisements for books and songs that John Powell kept for interest or purchase.
    - Course materials, notes, and lectures of John Powell, n.d., 37 items. (Box-folder 28:7)
    - Course materials, notes, and lectures of John Powell, n.d., 32 items. (Box-folder 28:8)
    - Introduction by John Powell for Winston Wilkinson's book on Traditional Ballads., January 25, 1942, 28:9 (Box-folder 28:9)
      TM, 19 pp.
    - Lyrics by John Powell and others, n.d., 36 items. (Box-folder 28:10)
    - Lyrics by John Powell and others, n.d., 61 items. (Box-folder 28:11)
    - Lyrics by John Powell and others, n.d., 31 items. (Box-folder 28:12)
    - Lyrics by John Powell and others, n.d., 22 items. (Box-folder 28:13)
    - Lyrics by John Powell and others, n.d., 48 items. (Box-folder 28:14)
    - Lyrics by John Powell and others, n.d., 86 items. (Box-folder 28:15)
    - Lyrics by John Powell, n.d., 60 items. (Box-folder 29:1)
    - Lyrics by John Powell, n.d., 5 items. (Box-folder 29:2)
    - Lyrics by John Powell, n.d., 14 items. (Box-folder 29:3)
    - Notebook of John Powell, n.d. (Box-folder 29:4)
      Powell kept notes about songs, Marcus Garvey, William Sherrill and stories about "Negroes."
    - Performance and program notes including a list of John Powell's performances, n.d., 88 items. (Box-folder 29:5)
    - Review of B. M. Steigman's play, The Unconquerable Tristan by John Powell, n.d., TM, 3 pp. (Box-folder 29:6)
    - Review of Daniel Gregory Mason's performance of The Chamber Music of Brahms by John Powell, n.d., TM, 5pp., and a handwritten draft. AN, 10 pp. (Box-folder 29:7)
    - Reviews by John Powell, n.d., 2 items. (Box-folder 29:8)
    - Reviews of John Powell, 1938; n.d., 17 items. (Box-folder 29:9)
    - Dirge, a piano duet by John Powell, March 20, 1928 (Box-folder 29:10)
      Musical score.
    - Piano duet Untitled 1, n.d., 2 TM, 6 pp. (Box-folder 29:11)
    - Piano duet Untitled 2, n.d., 6 TM, 48 pp. (Box-folder 29:12)
    - Gargoyle, A Romantic Opera, by John Powell, n.d., AN, 23 pp. 1 musical score. (Box-folder 29:13)
    - Compositions, n.d., 25 AN. (Box-folder 29:14)
      Some East and Central African Themes; Horn Fair, Essex House songbook, May-Day Carol, So Selfish Runs the Hare, The Poor Little Fisher Boy, Arise, Arise, The Old Dominion, Josh, Jarabaude, Christians Hope, Possum Tree, The Wedding of Miss Duck, Bonnie Blue Eyes, Betty Gooden, The First Blessing, Recess in Heaven, and Broken Octave.
    - Song The Three Jovial Huntsman by John Powell, November 20, 1934, AN, 1 p.2l. (Box-folder 29:15)
    - Speech and music introductions by John Powell, n.d., 38 items. (Box-folder 30:1)
    - Notes on Speeches, n.d. (Box-folder 30:2)
    - Stamps from the American Society of Composers, Authors, and Publishers, n.d., (ASCAP) 1 book of stamps. (Box-folder 30:3)
    - Stamp for the American Society of Composers, Authors, and Publishers, n.d., 1 ink stamper. (Box-folder 30:4)
  - B.Manuscripts: Others.
    (Music) Articles, artwork, lectures, radio scripts and other works, White Top Festival, and Virginia State Choral
    - Article on Daniel Gregory Mason, December.21, 1928, TS, 10 pp. New York World. (Box-folder 30:4)
    - Introduction to Hymn Collection of George Pullen Jackson., 1937, TM, 5pp. There is also a revision enclosed. (Box-folder 30:5)
    - Moses asks for a sign by Annabel Buchanan, n.d., TM, 10 pp. (Box-folder 30:6)
    - Recollections of a Courier of the Last Ten Days of the Army, n.d., TM, 13 pp. (Box-folder 30:7)
      A first hand account of life on the battlefield in the Civil War by an unidentified author, possibly named [Hawes].
    - Recording at the Fair, Reflections by Charles W. Freeman, 1979, TMs, 2 pp. (Box-folder 30:8)
    - Artwork, Egyptian Legend by Lelia C. Stiles, 1905, AN, 27 pp. (Box-folder 30:9)
      Hand made illustrated book and a birthday letter.
    - Artwork, n.d., 7 pp. (Box-folder 30:10)
      Sketches of John Powell and colleagues.
    - Artwork, unidentified, n.d., 6 items. (Box-folder 30:11)
    - Lectures on folksongs by Annabel Buchanan, n.d., TM, 11 pp. and notes. (Box-folder 30:12)
    - Miscellaneous writings and drawings, n.d., 8 AN, 11 pp. (Box-folder 30:13)
      The Pilgrim Spirit; notes on Austrian embroidery; notes on Pantomimic Dance; drawings of faces.
    - Notes on Appalachian folk singing by Cecil Sharp, n.d., AN, 2 pp. (Box-folder 30:14)
    - Notes, Virginia State Choral Festival, 1931-1934, 15 TM, 19 pp. about performances and programs. (Box-folder 30:15)
    - Notes, 1933-1939, TM, 23 pp. (Box-folder 30:16)
      White Top Festival contestants, program notes and folk music handout.
    - As Clouds Gather by Ben Burwell Johnston, Jr., n.d., TM, 22 pp. (Box-folder 30:17)
      Poems.
    - Crystals by Mary Cummings Eudy, n.d., AN, 8 pp. (Box-folder 30:18)
    - Tonight in the South, Station WAPI, May 12, 1934, 1 TS Mimeo, 2 pp. Radio script. (Box-folder 3:19)
      John Temple Graves talks about music in the South.
    - Gavotte by C. W. Von Gluck, n.d., TM, 16 pp. (Box-folder 3:20)
      Score.
    - Margaret's Minuet by Fred C. Hahr, n.d., TM, 11 pp. (Box-folder 3:21)
    - Summer Evening at Claremont by Beulah Bennett, n.d., TM, 3 pp. (Box-folder 3:22)
    - Sonate pour Piano by A. Z. Mathot, 1920, Printed, 13 pp. (Box-folder OS.)
    - Beauty, Experience, Pan Pikes, Sir Gawain and the Green Knight., n.d., TM, 11 pp. (Box-folder 3:23)
      Stories.
    - Black Terror by Harry Fitzhowell, n.d., TM, 17 pp. with handwritten notes. (Box-folder 3:24)
      Story.
    - The Princess Discontent by Helena Lefroy Caperton, n.d., TM, 20 pp. (Box-folder 3:25)
  - C. Manuscripts. Louise Burleigh Powell.
    Articles, cookbook, and plays.
    - How to Choose a Play, by Louise Powell, n.d., TM, 12 pp. (Box-folder 31:1)
    - The Theatre without Equipment, by Louise Powell, n.d., TM, 7 pp. (Box-folder 31:2)
    - Cookbook of [Burleigh family] including a recipe for soap, n.d. (Box-folder 31:3)
    - Notes on prospective plays by Louise Powell, n.d., 1 bound journal and loose notes. (Box-folder 31:4)
    - Beatrice by John and Louise Powell, June 1922, TM, 69 pp. (Box-folder 31:5)
    - Beatrice by John and Louise Powell, June 1922, TM, and AN, 209 pp. (Box-folder 31:6)
      TM rough draft of their play and correspondence with the publishers.
    - Elizabethans In Albemarle by Louise Powell, n.d., 1 TM, 13 pp. and stage instructions, TM, 3 pp. (Box-folder 31:7)
    - In Lilac Time by Louise Powell, n.d., TM, 96 pp. 2 copies. (Box-folder 31:8)
    - The Inevitable Scene by Louise Powell, 1918; 1935, TM, 32 pp. (Box-folder 31:9)
      There is also a letter (1935) from Beverley L. Britton, University of Richmond, who is returning a copy of the play with new revisions that she made while directing it.
    - Lunatics by Louise Powell, n.d., TM, 15 pp. (Box-folder 31:10)
    - The Merry Fiddle, a children's play and The Story of the Theatre with several revisions, n.d., TM, 3 pp. 2 TM, 21 pp. each. (Box-folder 31:11)
    - The Romantic Comedy by Louise Powell, n.d., TM, 27 pp. (Box-folder 31:12)
    - Sniffin Sid by [Louise Powell], n.d., 3 TM and AN drafts, 88 pp. (Box-folder 32:1)
    - The Spectre of the King, An Eastern Tragedy by Louise Powell, n.d., 4 TM copies, 155 pp. (Box-folder 32:2)
    - Strategem, by Louise Powell, n.d., TM, 44 pp. (Box-folder 32:3)
    - Through the Open Door of Abou Kalif, An Eastern Tale, 1919, TM, 51 pp. (Box-folder 32:4)
    - Wings of Memory by Louise Powell, n.d., TM, 19 pp. (Box-folder 32:5)
    - The Wooden Sword by Louise Powell, 1924, TM, 151 pp. and a draft TM, 44 pp. (Box-folder 32:6)
    - The Wooden Sword by Louise Powell, 1924, TM, 180 pp. 2 copies. (Box-folder 32:7)
    - The Spirit Mover by Louise Powell, n.d., AD, 10 pp. (Box-folder 32:8)
      Poem.
    - Review of Edna Turpin's novel, Echo Hill by Louise Powell, n.d., TM, 2 pp. (Box-folder 32:9)
    - Review of Barrett H. Clark's play, World Drama by Louise Powell, n.d., TM, 6 pp. (Box-folder 32:10)
    - Reviews and history of plays by Louise Powell, n.d., TM, 21 pp. with handwritten notes. (Box-folder 32:11)
    - Reviews of Louise Powells' plays, n.d., TM, 9 pp. (Box-folder 32:12)
    - Under Canvas by Louise Powell. n.d., TM, 27 pp. Two copies. (Box-folder 32:13)
      Short story.
    - Pocahontas at the Court of King James, Archedea, The Tea Doll, and The Lady with a Lamp by Louise Powell, n.d. (Box-folder 32:14)
      Short stories.
    - Dark Cloud by Louise Powell, submitted for publishing, n.d. (Box-folder 32:15)
      There are 4 copies (revisions) of it with a letter from Mary Block, of George T. Bye, Inc. Story.
  - D. Manuscripts: Others (Plays)
    - Coal by Minnie Brogan et al., n.d., TM, 13 pp. (Box-folder 33:1)
    - Gamer Gurton's Needle, n.d., TM, 40 pp. (Box-folder 33:2)
    - Hawaiian Pantomime by Frank Grandy, 1924, 1 bound volume. (Box-folder 33:3)
    - The Heretics by Boyce Loving, 1927, 1 bound volume. (Box-folder 33:4)
    - The Inevitable Camel's Pa for Louise Powell to review, December 10, 1922, TM, 6 pp. (Box-folder 33:5)
    - John Swift by Virginia Baker, n.d., TM, 25 pp. (Box-folder 33:6)
    - Judith, n.d., TM, 7pp. (Box-folder 33:7)
    - McFee's Cure, n.d., TM, 17 pp. (Box-folder 33:8)
    - The Mystery of the Kings Birth by Adair Archer, and staged by Louise Powell, n.d., TM, 27 pp. (Box-folder 33:9)
    - The Parable of Three Little Boys, March 1913, 11 pp. and other stories 2 pp. (Box-folder 33:10)
    - Playing with Fire by Amlie Rives, 1922, Act I, TM, 41 pp. Act II, TM, 39 pp. Act III, TM, 63 pp. (Box-folder 33:11)
    - The Prioress to the Penitent, n.d., TM, 23 pp. Poems with handwritten notes. (Box-folder 33:12)
    - The Prize MMMOOOooo., n.d., Three drafts. 3 TM, 3pp. (Box-folder 33:13)
    - Young Virginia, n.d., TM, 21 pp. (Box-folder 33:14)
    - Unidentified fragments from plays, n.d., TM and AN. (Box-folder 33:15)
- Series III: Printed Materials and Programs
  - A. Programs
    - 1. John Powell Programs
      - Programs, 1900-1909, 4 items. (Box-folder 34:1)
      - Programs, 1910-1919, 19 items. (Box-folder 34:2)
      - Programs, 1920-1924, 12 items. (Box-folder 34:3)
      - Programs, 1925-1927, 7 items. (Box-folder 34:4)
      - Programs, 1928-1929, 33 items. (Box-folder 34:5)
      - Programs, Carnegie Hall, 1929, 9 items. (Box-folder 34:6)
      - Programs, 1930-1931, 27 items. (Box-folder 34:7)
      - Programs, 1932-1934, 33 items. (Box-folder 34:8)
      - Programs, 1935-1939, 43 items. (Box-folder 34:9)
      - Programs, 1940-1949, 29 items. (Box-folder 34:10)
      - Programs, 1950-1959, 18 items. (Box-folder 35:1)
      - Programs, 1960-1969, 4 items. (Box-folder 35:2)
      - Programs, n.d., 61 items. (Box-folder 35:3)
      - Programs, n.d., 54 items. (Box-folder 35:4)
      - Programs, n.d., 3 items and 1 musical review. (Box-folder 35:OS)
    - 2. Other Programs
      - Programs, Louise Burleigh Powell, 1929; n.d., 2 items. (Box-folder 35:5)
      - Programs, Francis Warrington Dawson, 1913, 2 items. (Box-folder 35:6)
      - Programs, 1929, 26 items. (Box-folder 35:7)
      - Programs, 1930-1934, 35 items. (Box-folder 35:8)
      - Programs, 1935-1936, 21 items. (Box-folder 35:9)
      - Programs, 1937-1939, 29 items. (Box-folder 35:10)
      - Programs, 1940-1947, 43 items. (Box-folder 35:11)
      - Programs, 1948, 38 items. (Box-folder 36:1)
      - Programs, Virginia Federation of Music Clubs, 1948-1959, 2 items. (Box-folder 36:2)
      - Programs, Choir Festival, n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 36:3)
      - Programs, n.d., 38 items. (Box-folder 36:4)
    - 3. White Top Programs
      - Programs, Country and Folk Dancing, n.d., 6 items. (Box-folder 36:5)
      - Programs, 1938 (Box-folder 36:6)
  - B. News Clippings
    - Authored by Powell, 1928-1934, 9 items. (Box-folder 36:7)
    - Choral Festival, 1931-1936, 16 items. (Box-folder 36:8)
    - Critique, 1931-1950, 43 items. (Box-folder 36:9)
    - Debut/Anniversary, 1908-1938, 22 items. (Box-folder 36:10)
    - Family, 1899-1904, 7 items. (Box-folder 36:11)
    - Folk Music, 1934-1950, 40 items. (Box-folder 36:12)
    - Foreign, 1908-1930, 43 items. (Box-folder 36:13)
    - John Powell Day, 1951, 25 items. (Box-folder 36:14)
    - Lecture Recital, 1942, 18 items. (Box-folder 36:15)
    - Music, 1908-1958, 47 items. (Box-folder 36:16)
    - Music Festival, 1912-1950, 58 items. (Box-folder 36:17)
    - Musical Work, 1913-1963, 55 items. (Box-folder 36:18)
    - Personal, 1922-1958, 10 items. (Box-folder 36:19)
    - Photographs, 1912-1941, 21 items. (Box-folder 36:20)
    - Recitals, 1913-1959, 76 items. (Box-folder 36:21)
    - Recital, Aeolian Hall (NY/London), 1908-1914, 96 items. (Box-folder 37:1)
    - Recitals, 1912-1962, 71 items. (Box-folder 37:2)
    - Recitals, n.d., 61 items. (Box-folder 37:3)
    - Recitals, Overseas, 1908-1941, 32 items. (Box-folder 37:4)
    - Rescue of Miss Virginia Shepherd, 1925, 5 items. (Box-folder 37:5)
    - Richmond Female Seminary, 1931-1949, 13 items. (Box-folder 37:6)
    - Wresting, 1913, 5 items. (Box-folder 37:7)
    - Annabel Morris Buchanan, 1936-1938, 12 items. (Box-folder 37:8)
    - Louise Burleigh Powell, 1914-1942, 31 items. (Box-folder 37:9)
    - Choral Festival, 1932, 12 items. (Box-folder 37:10)
    - Education, 1929-1955, 6 items. (Box-folder 37:11)
    - Folk Song/Music, 1931-1953, 18 items. (Box-folder 37:12)
    - Foreign, 1912-1930, 7 items. (Box-folder 37:13)
    - Hans Kindler, 1933-1949, 8 items. (Box-folder 37:14)
    - Daniel Gregory Mason, 1926-1953, 9 items. (Box-folder 37:15)
    - Music, 1916-1963, 60 items. (Box-folder 37:16)
    - Music Festival, 1913-1950, 12 items. (Box-folder 37:17)
    - Others, 1922-1962, 86 items. (Box-folder 37:18)
    - Politics, 1919-1958, 23 items. (Box-folder 37:19)
    - Photographs, 1931, 1 item. (Box-folder 37:20)
    - Theater, 1926, 5 items. (Box-folder 37:21)
    - University of Virginia, n.d., 5 items. (Box-folder 37:22)
    - Week-ends at Nesscombe, 1911, 8 items. (Box-folder 37:23)
    - White Top Folk Festival, 1913-1935, 21 items. (Box-folder 37:24)
    - List of Articles in The Richmond Times-Dispatch and The Richmond News Leader, n.d., 1 item. (Box-folder 37:25)
- Series IV: Eugenics and Racial Integrity
  - A. Articles on Eugenics (Dissertations, broadsides, and speeches)
    - Petition from 144 citizens of King William County, Virginia, January 20, 1843, TMs, 3 pp. (Box-folder 38:1)
      To the General Assembly of Virginia. White residents issue a petition complaining that there are free mulattoes living on the land that was given to the Indian ancestors of the mulattoes. The petitioners write that the negroes could bring evil and they describe it as, "...the ready asylum of runaway slaves, and a secure harbor for every one who wishes concealment."
    - Amherst County Indians, 1896, TM, 1 p. (Box-folder 38:2)
      The Richmond Times-Dispatch.
    - U. S. Census Estimate of Indians in Virginia, 1900-1920, TM, 1 p. (Box-folder 38:3)
    - The Vardaman Idea, How the Governor of Mississippi Would Solve the Race Question, by Harris Dickson, The Saturday Evening Post, April 27, 1907, TM, 3 pp. (Box-folder 38:4)
    - A Negro Moses And His Plans For An African Exodus, The Literary Digest, 1921, Reprint. 2 pp. (Box-folder 38:5)
    - Constitution of the Anglo-Saxon Club of America, Anglo-Saxon Clubs Of America (ASCOA), 1923, TM, 20 pp. (Box-folder 38:6)
    - Instructions to Local Registrars and Other Agents in Administration of the Law to preserve Racial Integrity. The Virginia Health Bulletin, March 1924, Printed, 2 pp. (Box-folder 38:7)
    - The Racial Transformation of America by Madison Grant. The North American Review, March 1924, TM, 10 pp. (Box-folder 38:8)
    - Racial Characteristics as the Cause of the High Tuberculosis Death Rate among Negroes by Charles R. Grandy, The American Review of Tuberculosis, November 1924, Vol. X, No. 3. TM, 5 pp. (Box-folder 38:9)
    - The Sorrells case by John Powell, 1924, TM, 12 pp. (Box-folder 38:10)
    - Shall We All Be Mulattoes? The Literary Digest, March 7, 1925, TM, 2 pp. (Box-folder 38:11)
    - Let My People Go, by Earnest Sevier Cox, May 1925, TM, 36 pp. (Box-folder 38:12)
    - Who Are Pure Nordics?, August 1925, TM, 4 pp. (Box-folder 38:13)
      A Review of Some Insidious Literature on Race Propaganda and the Answer. The Progressive, August 1, 1925.
    - The Negro In The North The Commonwealth, 1927, TM, 4 pp. (Box-folder 38:14)
      A Weekly Review of Literature, The Arts, and Public Affairs.
    - Race Deterioration and Destruction with Special Reference to the American People by Alex Hrdlicka, January 6, 1928, TM, 3 pp. Speech. (Box-folder 38:15)
      Curator, Division of Physical Anthropology, U. S. National Museum, Smithsonian Institution at the Third Race Betterment Conference, Battle Creek, Michigan.
    - Racial Integrity Legislation, Virginia House Bill 25, and Virginia House Bill 2, February 1928, TM, 5 pp. (Box-folder 38:16)
      House Bill 25 requires applicants for a marriage license to state under oath their racial status as well as have an affidavit showing their accurate race. House Bill 2 is intended to add a definition of a colored person to the present law which only defines a white person.
    - Abraham Lincoln On The Question Of Negro Colonization by Earnest Sevier Cox, 1956, TM, 4 pp. (Box-folder 38:17)
    - Brief Story of the Negro Race Repatriation Movement by Earnest Sevier Cox, 1956, TM, 1 p. (Box-folder 38:18)
    - Race and Morality by Matt Koehl, March 1959, TM, 12 pp. (Box-folder 38:19)
      Right, A Journal of Forward Looking American Nationalism.
    - Students, White and Negro, Red Dupes, May 1960, TM, 4 pp. (Box-folder 38:20)
      J. Edgar Hoover Exposes Youth as Target of Communists, excerpts from Fact-Finding Memo B, Grass Roots League.
    - A Case Study of the Virginia Racial Integrity Legislation by Brian William Thomson, March 1978, Part 1-2. TM, 255 pp. Dissertation. (Box-folder 38:21-22)
    - Bloated Caesars by Earnest Sevier Cox, n.d., TM, 7 pp. (Box-folder 38:23)
      A layman's estimate of the Supreme Court.
    - The Last Stand by John Powell, n.d., 1 photocopy of twelve newspaper articles that depict families with negro blood in their ancestry but are living as white. (Box-folder 38:24)
    - The Last Stand by John Powell, n.d. (Box-folder 38:25)
      1 scrapbook of twelve newspaper articles (pasted into a notebook) that depict families with negro blood in their ancestry but are living as white.
    - Citation of Cases Showing Racial Amalgamation and Decadence of Racial Sense, n.d., TM, 12 pp. (Box-folder 38:26)
    - Education for What? Suicide or Survival! by Mrs. J. Wyatt Payne, n.d., TM, 16 pp. (Box-folder 38:27)
    - Homo Africanus by L. M. Hussey, The American Mercury, n.d., TM, 8 pp. (Box-folder 38:28)
    - Mission Work among Some Cherokee Remnants in Virginia by Arthur P. Gray, Jr., n.d., TM, 3 pp. (Box-folder 38:29)
    - The Negro's Reaction towards Subject of Amalgamation by Gordon B. Hancock, n.d., TM, 2 pp. (Box-folder 38:30)
    - Oscar W. Firkins Selected Essays, n.d., TM, 3 pp. (Box-folder 38:31)
    - The School Situation at Clinton, Tennessee by Earnest Sevier Cox, n.d., TM, 4 pp. (Box-folder 38:32)
    - The Segregation Issue: Suggestions Regarding the Maintenance of State Autonomy by William Old, n.d., TM, 29 pp. (Box-folder 38:33)
    - Shall America Remain White? by W. A. Plecker, n.d., TM, 9 pp. (Box-folder 38:34)
    - Virginia's Attempt to Adjust the Color Problem by W. A. Plecker, n.d., TM, 12 pp. (Box-folder 38:35)
    - Title page of White America by Earnest S. Cox, n.d., 1 printed. 4 pp. (Box-folder 38:36)
    - Mass Meetings to be held to protest for the annulment of the fourteenth amendment, January 23, 29, n.y., 2 items, 2 pp. Broadsides. (Box-folder 38:37)
    - Questionnaire form for members of Who's Who about the age of parents in relation to the achievements of children, n.d., TM, 1 p. (Box-folder 38:38)
    - Cartoon illustration making fun of "a dining room boy" n.d., 1 illustration. (Box-folder 38:39)
    - On Knowing Ourselves First by George Pullen Jackson, Vanderbilt University, n.d., 1 illustration, 15 pp. Speech. (Box-folder 38:40)
    - What the Negro Wants, n.d., TMs, 3 pp. Speech. (Box-folder 38:41)
    - Speech by [John Powell] about America as a homogenous nation, n.d., TMs, 9 pp. (Box-folder 38:42)
    - Speech by [John Powell] about a homogenous America, n.d., TMs, 7 pp. (Box-folder 38:43)
    - Notes on the history of defining a "colored person" n.d., TMs, 4 pp. (Box-folder 38:44)
    - Racial Integrity Bill for the District of Columbia, n.d., TMs, 2 pp. (Box-folder 38:45)
    - Notes on the Anglo-Saxon Clubs of America. (A.S.C.O.A.), n.d., AN, 4 pp. (Box-folder 38:46)
    - Constitutional Government in Grave Danger by unidentified author, n.d., TMs, 5 pp. (Box-folder 38:47)
      The article supports the Constitution of the United States and points out a concern that the Supreme Court is executing too much power in its interpretations of the Constitution, particularly in the last twenty five years when President Roosevelt came into office.
    - Legislation. Court instructions for the jury in the case of Commonwealth v. Ray Wynn, n.d., TMs, 5 pp. (Box-folder 38:48)
      There is an indictment on Ray Wynn who, as a colored man, married a white woman, May Wilson. The Commonwealth of Virginia must prove that she is white and that he is colored, and that they were officially married. Wynn would also have to know at the time of the marriage that he is part negro.
    - Notes by John Powell for House Bill [No. 2 and No. 85.], n.d., 2 AN, 6 pp. (Box-folder 38:49)
      Powell writes about a bill that is needed to define a colored person in accord with the definition of whites. Powell writes that the law since 1910 states that a colored person is defined by a certain fraction of African blood. The Virginia Racial Integrity Act of 1924 defines a white person as having no trace of any blood other than Caucasian or having less than 1/16 of Indian blood.
    - Flyer distributed by The League to Annul the Fourteenth Amendment, n.d., TL, 1 p. (Box-folder 38:50)
      Judge Henry Edwin Bolte is promoting a nationwide movement to annul the 14th amendment. He believes that by eliminating the negroes from politics, "white people will not have to work under a [sic] negro officials." He claims that "negro suffrage was obtained by fraud."
    - Signed petition supporting the Virginia Racial Integrity Bill of 1926, n.d., TMs, 6 pp. (Box-folder 38:51)
    - Flyer, The Peace Movement of Ethiopia, n.d., TM, 1 p. (Box-folder 38:52)